I'm a neuroscientist, a professor at the University of California.
أنا عالم أعصاب، بروفيسور في جامعة كاليفورنيا.
And over the past 35 years,
وخلال ال 35 سنة الماضية،
I've studied behavior
أدرس السلوك.
on the basis of everything from genes
لكن إستناداً على كل شئ من الجينات
through neurotransmitters, dopamine, things like that,
عبر أجهزة الإرسال العصبية، والدوبامين ، واشياء من هذا القبيل ،
all the way through circuit analysis.
على طول الطريق عبر أغراض التحليل.
So that's what I normally do.
أذاً هذا ما أفعله عادةً.
But then, for some reason,
ولكن، لسبب ما،
I got into something else, just recently.
تحولت الى شئ آخر، فقط مؤخراً.
And it all grew out of one of my colleagues asking me
وكل شئ بدأ من طلب من زميلي
to analyze a bunch of brains
لتحليل بعض الأدمغة
of psychopathic killers.
لقتلة سيكوباتيين.
And so this would be the typical talk I would give.
وهذا سيكون بالضبط الحديث الذي سأقدمه.
And the question is, "How do you end up with a psychopathic killer?"
والسؤال هو، " كيف ينتهي بك الحال الى قاتل سيكوباتي؟"
What I mean by psychopathic killer
ما أعنيه بقاتل سيكوباتي
are these people, these types of people.
هو أولئك الناس، هذه النوعية من الناس.
And so some of the brains that I've studied
وبعض الأدمغة التي درستها
are people you know about.
هم أناس تعلمون عنهم.
When I get the brains I don't know what I'm looking at.
عندما أحصل على الأدمغة لا أعرف الى ماذا أنظر.
It's blind experiments. They also gave me normal people and everything.
لقد كانت تجربة عمياء. أعطوني أشخاص عاديين وكل شئ.
So I've looked at about 70 of these.
لذا فحصت حوالي 70 من هذا.
And what came up was a number of pieces of data.
ورجعت ونظرت الى عدد من مجموعات البيانات.
So we look at these sorts of things theoretically,
اذاً نحن ننظر لنوع من تلك الأشياء نظرياً،
on the basis of genetics,
على أساس علم الجينات،
and brain damage, and interaction with environment,
وتلف الدماغ، والتفاعل مع البيئة،
and exactly how that machine works.
وبالتحديد كيف تعمل تلك الماكينة.
So we're interested in exactly where in the brain,
اذاً نحن مهتمون بأين تحديداً في الدماغ،
and what's the most important part of the brain.
وما هو الجزء الأهم في الدماغ.
So we've been looking at this:
اذاً كنا ننظر في هذا.
the interaction of genes,
تفاعل الجينات،
what's called epigenetic effects,
ما يسمى بالآثار اللاجينية
brain damage, and environment,
تلف الدماغ، والبيئة،
and how these are tied together.
وكيف أنهما مرتبطان.
And how you end up with a psychopath, and a killer,
وكيف يتنهي بك الحال الى سايكوباتي، وقاتل،
depends on exactly when the damage occurs.
يعتمد على متى حدث التلف تحديداً.
It's really a very precisely timed thing.
أنه شئ يحدده التوقيت بدقة.
You get different kinds of psychopaths.
سيكون لديك أنواع مختلفة من السايكوباتيين.
So we're going along with this. And here's, just to give you the pattern.
ولذلك فاننا سنمضي على هذا النحو، فقط لإعطائكم الفكرة.
The pattern is that those people, every one of them I looked at,
الفكرة هي أن هؤلاء الناس، كل واحد منهم نظرت اليه،
who was a murderer, and was a serial killer,
من الذين كانوا قتلة، وكان قاتلاً متسلسلاً،
had damage to their orbital cortex,
لديه تلف في القشرة المدارية.
which is right above the eyes, the orbits,
التي تقع أعلى العين بالضبط، المدارات.
and also the interior part of the temporal lobe.
وأيضاً الجزء الداخلي من الصدغ.
So there is the pattern that every one of them had,
اذاً هناك فكرة أن أي منهم لديه،
but they all were a little different too.
لكن كان هناك إختلاف صغير بينهم أيضاً.
They had other sorts of brain damage.
لديهم أنواع أخرى من تلف الدماغ.
A key thing is that
الفكرة الرئيسية هي
the major violence genes,
جينات العنف الرئيسية،
it's called the MAO-A gene.
تسمى جين MAO-A.
And there is a variant of this gene that is in the normal population.
وهناك تعدد لهذا الجين في الناس العاديين.
Some of you have this. And it's sex-linked.
لدى بعضكم هذا. وهي مرتبطة بالجنس.
It's on the X chromosome. And so in this way
وهي في الكروموسوم X. ولذا بهذه الطريقة
you can only get it from your mother.
يمكنك فقط أخذها من والدتك.
And in fact this is probably why mostly men, boys,
وفي الحقيقة هذا على الأرجح السبب في أن معظمهم من الرجال ،
are psychopathic killers,
الأولاد، هم قتلة سايكوباتيين،
or are very aggressive.
و عدوانيين جداً.
Because a daughter can get one X from the father,
لأن البنت يمكنها أخذ كروموسوم X من أبيها،
one X from the mother, it's kind of diluted out.
وكروموسوم X من أمها، وهو نوع من التمييع.
But for a son, he can only get
لكن بالنسبة للولد، يمكنه أخذ كروموسوم X
the X chromosome from his mother.
فقط من أمه.
So this is how it's passed from mother to son.
وبهذه الكيفية ينتقل من الأم الى الولد.
And it has to do with too much brain serotonin during development,
وعليها أن تفعل أكثر مما يجب مع السيروتونين خلال النمو.
which is kind of interesting because serotonin
الشئ المثير للإهتمام لأن السيروتونين
is supposed to make you calm and relaxed.
يفُترض أنه يجعلك هادئاً ومسترخياً.
But if you have this gene, in utero
لكن اذا كان لديك هذا الجين، في الرحم
your brain is bathed in this,
سيغسل دماغك في هذا.
so your whole brain becomes insensitive to serotonin,
لذا يصبح الدماغ برمته غير مكترث بالسيروتونين.
so it doesn't work later on in life.
اذاً لا يعمل لاحقاً.
And I'd given this one talk in Israel,
وقد قدمت هذا الحديث سابقاً في إسرائيل،
just this past year.
في العام الماضي فقط
And it does have some consequences.
وأن لديه عواقب.
Theoretically what this means
نظرياً ما يعنيه هذا
is that in order to express this gene,
هو أنه من أجل شرح هذا الجين،
in a violent way,
بطريقة عنيفة ،
very early on, before puberty,
باكراً جداً، قبل سن البلوغ،
you have to be involved in something that is really traumatic --
عليك أن تكون مشاركاً في شيء حقيقةً مؤلم ،
not a little stress, not being spanked or something,
ليس إجهاد خفيف، ليس أن تُضرب أو شئ هكذا.
but really seeing violence,
لكن حقيقةً تشهد العنف،
or being involved in it, in 3D.
أو أن تكون مشاركاً فيه، بثلاثة أبعاد.
Right? That's how the mirror neuron system works.
صحيح؟ هكذا يعمل النظام العصبي العاكس.
And so, if you have that gene,
ولذا، اذا كان لديك ذلك الجين،
and you see a lot of violence
ورأيت الكثير من العنف
in a certain situation,
في وضع معيّن ،
this is the recipe for disaster, absolute disaster.
هذا هو وصف الكارثة، كارثة مطلقة.
And what I think might happen in these areas of the world,
وما أعتقد أنه ربما يحصل في هذه الأجزاء من العالم،
where we have constant violence,
حينما يكون لديك عنف مستمر،
you end up having generations of kids
سينتهي بك الحال بأجيال من الأطفال
that are seeing all this violence.
شهدوا كل هذا العنف.
And if I was a young girl, somewhere in a violent area,
واذا كنت فتاة صغيرة، في مكان ما في منطقة عنف،
you know, a 14 year old, and I want to find a mate,
تعرفون، عمر 14 سنة، وأريد العثور على صديق،
I'd find some tough guy, right, to protect me.
سأجد شخص عنيف، صحيح، لحمايتي.
Well what the problem is this tends to concentrate these genes.
حسناً المشكلة هي أن هذا يميل الى تركيز هذه الجينات.
And now the boys and the girls get them.
والآن الأولاد والبنات يأخذونها.
So I think after several generations,
لذا أعتقد أنه بعد عدة أجيال،
and here is the idea, we really have a tinderbox.
وها هي الفكرة، حقيقة يكون لدينا صندوق الحريق.
So that was the idea.
اذا كانت هذه الفكرة.
But then my mother said to me, "I hear you've been going around talking
لكن عندها قالت لي أمي، " سمعت أنك تجري حديثاً
about psychopathic killers.
حول القتلة السايكوباتيين .
And you're talking as if you come from a normal family."
وأنت تتحدث كأنك جئت من أسرة عادية."
I said, "What the hell are you talking about?"
قلت، " بحق الجحيم عن ماذا تتحدثين؟"
She then told me about our own family tree.
أخبرتني عن شجرة أسرتنا.
Now she blamed this on my father's side, of course.
والآن ألقت باللوم على جانب أسرة أبي، بالطبع.
This was one of these cases, because she has no violence in her background,
كانت هذه أحدى الحالات، لأنها لم يكن لديها عنف ماضيها.
but my father did.
لكن كان لأبي خلفية.
Well she said, "There is good news and bad news.
حسناً قالت، " هناك أخبار سارة وأخبار سيئة.
One of your cousins is Ezra Cornell, founder of Cornell university.
أحد أبناء عمومتنا هو عزرا كورنيل، مؤسس جامعة كورنيل.
But the bad news is that your cousin is also Lizzie Borden.
لكن الأخبار السيئة هي أن بنت عمك هي أيضاً ليزي بوردن.
Now I said, "Okay, so what? We have Lizzie."
الآن قلت، " حسناً، وماذا في ذلك؟ لدينا ليزي."
She goes, "No it gets worse, read this book."
أردفت، " لا الموضوع أسوأ، أقرأ هذا الكتاب."
And here is this "Killed Strangely," and it's this historical book.
وهذا هو " مقتل الغريب،" وهذا هو الكتاب التاريخي.
And the first murder
وأول قاتل
of a mother by a son
لأم من قبل ولدها،
was my great-great-great-great-great-great-grandfather.
كان جد جد جد جد جد جدي.
Okay, so that's the first case of matricide.
حسناً، كان ذلك أول حالة لقاتل أمه.
And that book is very interesting. Because it's about witch trials,
وذلك الكتاب مثير جداً للإهتمام. لأنه كان عن محاكمات السحرة،
and how people thought back then.
وكيف فكّر الناس في ذلك الوقت.
But it doesn't stop there.
لكنها لم تتوقف هناك.
There were seven more men, on my father's side,
كان هناك سبعة رجال إضافيين، من جانب أبي،
starting then, Cornells, that were all murderers.
بدأوا حينها، من أسرة كورنيل، كانوا جميعهم قتلة.
Okay, now this gives one a little pause.
حسناً ، هذا يعطي الآن وقفة صغيرة.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Because my father himself,
لأن والدي نفسه،
and my three uncles, in World War II,
وأعمامي الثلاثة، في الحرب العالمية الثانية،
were all conscientious objectors, all pussycats.
عانوا جميعاً من عذاب الضمير، وكانوا قطط رقيقة.
But every once in a while, like Lizzie Borden, like three times a century,
لكن في كل فترة من الوقت، مثل ليزي بوردن، كثلاث مرات في القرن،
and we're kind of due.
ونحن على مقربة من ذلك.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
So the moral of the story is:
اذاً معنى القصة هو،
people in glass houses shouldn't throw stones.
الناس في البيوت من زجاج لا يجب أن يلقوا بالحجارة.
But more likely is this.
لكن هذا مرجح أكثر .
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
And we had to take action. Now our kids found out about it.
ويتوجب علينا أخذ فعل. الآن عرف أولادنا عن هذا.
And they all seemed to be OK.
ويبدو أنهم جميعاً بخير.
But our grandkids are going to be kind of concerned here.
لكن أحفادنا سيكونوا نوعاً ما قلقين من هذا .
So what we've done is I've started to do PET scans
لذا ما فعلناه هو أنني بدأت بعمل مسوحات مقطعية
of everybody in the family.
لأي شخص في الأسرة.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
We started to do PET scans, EEGs and genetic analysis
بدأنا عمل مسوحات مقطعية، وتحليل وراثي وتخطيط دماغي
to see where the bad news is.
لنعرف أين تكمن الأخبار السيئة.
Now the only person -- it turns out
الآن الشخص الوحيد، أتضح
one son and one daughter, siblings,
ولد واحد وبنت واحدة، أخوين،
didn't get along and their patterns are exactly the same.
لم يتفقا. والأنماط هي نفسها تماماً.
They have the same brain, and the same EEG.
لديهم نفس الدماغ، ونفس التخطيط الدماغي.
And now they are close as can be.
والآن هم أقرب ما يكون.
But there's gonna be bad news somewhere.
لكن ستكون هناك أخبار سيئة في مكان ما.
And we don't know where it's going to pop up.
ولا نعرف أين ستظهر.
So that's my talk.
اذاً ذلك هو حديثي.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)